I have a prior commitment.
We really should value our commitments.
- Hey!
- I know you'll harass Bahay Aruga
until you get their land.
A kid died there.
Do you have something to do with it?
The theme is water goddess realness.
I want it to be simple.
Didn't I tell you that?
This is for us. We deserve it.
I'm the one you'll marry, Hans. Not my image.
How's your project with Joyce
in the orphanage?
There are lots to be repaired.
Why are they renovating it?
I'm already buying that land.
I need to use force.
I'm begging you. Leave us alone.
Stop it.
You're doing that to scare the people off?
Why don't you try me?
Liam!
Liam, get out of there!
- Mom, that's enough!
- Liam, get out of there!
- Mom, let's stop this. Please.
- Madam!
- No.
- Liam!
Joanne?
- Where's Liam?
- What?
Liam!
Where are you, Liam?
- Get out of there!
- Mommy!
What's going on?
- Well...
- Liam!
- Liam.
- Joanne, Liam is not here.
Don't hide your son.
First, your son poisoned my daughter's mind.
And now, he's trying to have
an affair with her.
That's how good your son is. He's so great!
Watch your mouth!
I didn't raise my son
to become a bad person.
So stop!
- What?
- You raised him to be a flirt.
Your neighbors know that
he was born out of wedlock.
You're way out of line!
That's too much!
You're too much!
Aunt Tess, please stop!
That's enough! Stop.
Madam, stop, please.
That's enough. Please stop.
Aunt Tess! Mom, that's enough!
- Madam!
- You're so mean!
How dare you come to my house!
Mom! Mom! What's going on?
Madam!
What's happening here?
- Wait, wait. Hold on.
- Oh my God!
- What's this?
- A fight scene?
You, you!
You're all doing fine.
But my daughter isn't!
You're all great!
You have no right to talk to me that way
in my own house!
- Stop!
- Mom, let her be. Let it slide.
Joyce, please!
The nerve of your cheap mom
to come here and start a fight.
Via, can you not?
Let's just help them fix things.
Fix things?
You started this mess.
I didn't come here to fight, Via.
Then let me start the fight.
- Oh my!
- Via! Why?
Why? I should have done that
a long time ago.
Hey!
Excuse me!
Sir Liam stopped liking you
because you're a brat!
- What did you say?
- Yes, you're a brat!
Let me handle this!
I've been holding back
dealing with this awful girl!
Yes?
The design is so classy.
But your attitude is bad!
You're just a piece of trash.
What did you say?
I said, you're an ugly, atrocious trash!
Hey. I...
am not... trash!
How dare you!
Take it back. Take it back.
Hey! You two, stop!
Via...
Via, please, let me explain. Let me...
Let's talk. Hear me out.
I'll explain everything.
Joyce, we talked already. Didn't we?
We talked, lady-to-lady.
I asked you if you had an affair with Liam.
You denied it.
Well... no mistress will confess.
Joyce, let's go.
Joyce... come on.
- Liam, what are you doing?
- Come on. Come with me.
- Joyce.
- Let's go!
- Liam!
- Liam.
Where are you taking my daughter?
Liam!
Liam, what... what are you doing?
Why are we here?
Do you think running away
will solve anything?
Joyce, tell me.
- What's the meaning of what happened?
- I don't know!
All I know is a lot of people
are getting hurt.
So, this is wrong.
Can't we make it right?
How can we do that?
Tell me, Liam. How can we make this right?
With all the people you're hurting,
how can you make this right?
Be thankful that you and Via
are still okay.
Joyce, Joyce.
What is it this time?
Joyce...
Joyce, I love you.
I love you, but...
But what?
But I can't leave Via.
Joyce, Joyce.
The problem with you is your selfishness.
You don't care about others!
You make decisions based on
what's convenient for you, Liam!
You don't care about others.
So, you deserve what you have right now!
You're full of regrets
for the things you've done wrong
because you can't stand by your decisions!
You never bothered to take a leap of faith...
Mr. Herrera.
Who are you?
I finally found you...
Liam.
Intoy?
How are you, bro?
Give it to me.
I need to do something about this.
- Bro. Bro. Give it back.
- Intoy.
- Intoy, I need to do something.
- Give it back!
I have to do something with it, Intoy!
- Give it back.
- Intoy!
I said give it to me.
What's wrong with you?
What's the matter with you?
What do you want to change this time?
Isn't it clear to you, Liam?
There's a price to pay
whenever you use that typewriter.
Intoy, what are you saying?
What's the price to pay?
Everything's clear to me now, Liam.
Our meeting wasn't an accident.
Who are you? What do you know?
I'm the owner of this typewriter.
And whenever someone
uses this typewriter...
I am reminded of my past...
of my life story...
and the curse of this typewriter.
Intoy...
I'm immortal, Liam.
I've been alive for a long time.
And I'm set to suffer forever
because of this typewriter.
I used this for my personal gains.
To ruin someone else's life.
Intoy, Intoy, what are you talking about?
Are you going insane?
Liam...
Let me show you.
[Sabel, Diego]
There used to be a man
wearing a woven bag on his head
during the Japanese occupation.
He hides his face in that bag...
so he can betray his fellowmen.
There are rebels here. Identify them! Hurry!
Did you know what he gets in return?
A promise from the foreign invaders.
Don't kills us, please! Please, please.
- Jose!
- Please, don't kill me.
- Please, don't kill me!
Jose!
Sister!
No, no!
Don't believe him! No!
How dare you! You're a monster! Animal!
Don't!
Animals!
Other Filipinos call him... a traitor.
But behind that bag...
the man they call a monster,
also has a heart.
Sabel?
Sabel.
Sabel...
Please, take this.
You may have it for dinner.
Can you please leave me alone, Intoy?
Sabel, I don't have any bad intentions.
That's enough.
I just want to give you my harvest, Sabel.
I already have a boyfriend, Intoy.
I told you. I can never return your feelings.
You should stop
or focus your attention on someone else.
I'm sorry.
I still have lots to do at home.
Sabel, please.
Please accept this.
I harvested it for you.
Hey!
Are you harassing my girlfriend? Are you?
Diego.
- What? Are you harassing my girlfriend?
- Diego!
Diego!
Diego, please. Stop!
Are you harassing her?
Diego.
Diego! Diego!
Let's go.
That's enough.
Stop. Stop it. That's enough, Diego.
Let's go.
Enough.
The man wearing a bag in his head...
didn't notice that the anger
and the desire to be loved...
had consumed him.
[Diego Ignacio]
And a monster was born.
Are all the names on this list?
He used the typewriter to get even.
He let his feelings consume him.
Until his love turned into hatred and wrath.
No, no, no, no. Please, please, please.
Please, have mercy. Please, please.
Sabel, leave.
- Sabel!
- Please...
You might get harmed.
Please, please. Let go of him.
We are innocent.
Please, please.
Sabel!
But the man wearing a bag in his head
did worse than betrayal...
in his desire to get the woman he loves.
We're innocent. Please, let her go.
We're not rebels.
Let her go!
No! No, no, no.
I'm begging you.
My husband and I are innocent.
Are you sure?
- No!
- Yes, I'm sure.
No. No, please.
No. No, no, no.
Diego! No!
Diego!
Diego! Diego!
You're a monster! Traitor!
Animals!
Sabel!
You?
You, monster! Traitor!
Take this woman to the camp.
No, no.
We have a deal. She stays alive.
We have a deal...
You're heartless, Intoy!
Animal! You're a monster!
I can't let this woman live.
No! Don't kill her! Don't kill her.
Please, give her to me. No!
Curse you, Intoy!
You will pay for all your sins!
A monster like you will suffer forever!
You, monster!
Sabel!
Sabel.
The monster I'm telling you about
is here, Liam.
I am that monster.
Liam, I went crazy because of what happened.
I forgot about everything wrong that I did.
I roamed the streets.
I didn't notice that I don't age.
I am immortal, Liam.
I don't notice time passing by
because of my miserable life.
When I met you...
it was not the first time
our paths have crossed.
Something is pulling me closer to you.
And that's because my typewriter
is in your family's care.
Then we bumped into each other
under the billboard.
You can have this.
Thank you, bro.
Does it mean the curse was passed on to me?
You probably know now,
that whenever you use the typewriter
to change your life...
there will be a price to pay...
just like when you first used the typewriter.
You wished for Joyce to be happy.
The wishes you wrote from your heart
came true.
But your son with Joyce
disappeared in this world.
Dex, your son...
Along with it, as you climb to the top...
it devours you.
It makes you more greedy.
You were able to abuse powerless people.
Are you sure our farmlands won't be affected?
Someone told me to ask you for a permit.
Don't worry.
I have my staff working on it already.
But for now...
please accept it.
A little help from Casa Fuerte.
Thank you.
You're welcome, Mister Nestor.
We'll go ahead.
Be safe.
You sold your soul to the devil.
Is this complete?
Yes, Boss.
We'll be in trouble if something's missing.
Boss, I'm sure it's complete.
Big bro, I got the money.
I will put it in Casa Fuerte.
These are the memories
in the past seven years
that I cannot remember.
Intoy...
is it true that I became an evil person?
If you think that you're the only one
who became a monster
for changing your life...
you're wrong.
You created another monster.
What do you mean?
Ramon's henchman...
Lando.
Boss, I'm sorry.
Sir, what's that?
This?
Coffee.
- Stop him.
- Sir, hold on.
What's inside your bag?
Can I see it?
Go ahead!
Try to fight.
Sir, it's positive.
Okay.
Bring him to the police station.
By simply bumping into him...
he was fated to get arrested
and change his ways inside the prison.
But... what?
You changed it.
You changed the story.
Lando's life changed too.
Everyone who's getting off,
we've arrived in Huseña.
Hurry up, get off.
You're the reason he was overcome by evil.
You changed what was fated to happen.
You were unaware that stories and lives
were affected by it.
Get in.
Is there anyone else going to Segunda?
Boss.
- Is there still a seat?
- Yes.
Segunda!
He got into the bus that you were in.
He stayed free. And continue doing evil.
Until...
He became Ramon's henchman.
When you saw the typewriter...
Bro!
What did you do?
You chose to bring Joyce back to life.
Despite all my warnings.
"Don't do it. There's a price to pay".
Joyce came back to life.
You wished Joyce wasn't
stuck in your messy life.
You didn't break up with your girlfriend.
Joyce.
Hans?
Surprise.
- What are you doing here?
- Hello.
I asked Miss Megan.
She told me today is your big scene with...
Josh and Maxine.
So as a worried suitor,
I came here to make sure you're okay.
Please keep safe.
Hans...
nothing wrong will happen to me.
Especially now that the best defender
in the country is here.
You didn't tell Joyce your true feelings.
I need to talk to Hans.
Do you know where he is?
I will tell you something important
about your investigation.
The suspect in the murder of
the Casa Fuerte worker...
The man we saw in the video,
caught by the CCTV camera...
I know him. His name is Lando.
It's Lando.
That devil only works for one man.
- Uncle, wait.
- Quiet.
Hans!
Hi.
- Hey, Via.
- What are you doing here?
Nothing. Taking time to relax.
This is Uncle Edmond. Have you met him?
Joyce's dad.
Yes, you are Joyce's father. Right.
Sorry, I saw you on the news.
I'm Via.
Liam's girlfriend.
Do you want to watch Joyce on the set?
Come on, I'll go with you.
Yes, sure. Okay. Let's go.
Uncle, let's talk about that in a safe place.
- Let's go back to Manila together.
- Okay.
I'll just talk to Joyce.
I'll say goodbye to her.
Papa...
There's something you need to know.
Joyce didn't know anything
about Ramon's evil doings.
And because of that...
Via and Lando didn't try to kill her.
They targeted Edmond instead of her.
Cut!
Good take.
Lovely. Perfect.
Joyce...
Good job.
Edmond, the problem is
you already know too much.
You should go blind.
Blind?
Lando, don't.
You're a demon!
Don't do it, Lando!
Let go...
Don't.
It's too late for mercy.
Remember when I asked you,
if Joyce's death brought something good?
She was able to send
all the culprits to jail.
But because you altered the events
and brought Joyce back to life,
the culprit remains free.
The devil continues with his wicked ways.
You don't want to give up
this orphanage, huh?
Now, you'll be forced to leave this place.
That's gasoline.
Are you setting the orphanage on fire?
Sister! Sister!
They're going to set the orphanage on fire!
Sister!
Ouch!
- Let's go!
- Catch him!
Help! Police!
Help!
Help.
You got us tired.
You really want to be chased?
You even bit me.
What's happening to him?
We don't know, Boss.
He suddenly stopped running.
Do you think he's having a heart attack?
You should have stayed out of this, kid.
Please, help me.
Finish the job so we can leave.
Mom...
Forgive me...
Forgive me, Sep.
How dare you, Vergil.
You're a monster. A monster!
We both got addicted
to using the typewriter.
We both used it for our own gains.
Liam...
You don't notice it, but...
you're slowly becoming a monster.
You have the same fate as mine.
But now, Liam...
you already know the price you have to pay.
Like what happened to me...
I was cursed to suffer forever.
Liam, tell me...
Tell me...
that you still want to use this typewriter.
I want to apologize.
Honestly, I understand Joanne.
She's just protecting her daughter.
If only we could talk calmly,
I would tell her to...
To let our children do what they want.
Do you want it, Joyce?
Want what?
Do you and Liam like each other?
Aunt Tess, about what happened
between Liam and me,
about our...
kiss.
Sorry, Auntie, for not saying no.
I didn't stop him.
Maybe subconsciously...
I wanted it to happen too.
Even though I know it was wrong.
You know, Joyce...
nothing is wrong...
when someone truly loves.
But there's a right way to give in
to what the heart wants.
I wish, somehow...
you thought of the people who will get hurt.
That's what we did wrong.
Do you want me to talk to Liam?
So you can correct everything?
So you can explain to everyone who got hurt?
So that you and Liam can be free?
No one else should use this typewriter.
How can you break free from the curse?
I don't know.
Maybe I deserve to suffer...
for all the wrong things I did.
Joyce?
Liam, son...
What's going on?
Mom.
Joyce.
I have something to tell you.
Mom, please, sit down.
Joyce, please, hear me out.
Please, I'm begging you.
Please.
Come on, Joyce. Please.
Good evening, Tess, Joyce.
I'm Intoy.
Hans.
Hi.
My fellow loser. Come.
Sit, sit, sit.
Wait.
Why did you ask me to come here?
No reason.
I just want to...
talk to someone
who's going through the same thing.
I think you've had too much drink.
Let's go.
Let's go home. I'll drive you home.
Hans...
I have no one to go home to.
Can't you join me?
Even for a while?
Let's drink.
We'll show them...
They can't be the only ones happy.
I know this is hard to believe.
But please, Mom, Joyce, believe me.
I'm telling the truth. Please, believe me.
Now, I get a grasp of everything I saw...
that I couldn't understand.
I saw that you and Joyce are married...
and then...
you have a child...
who looks exactly like Sep,
but is named Dex.
Are all of these true?
- Are they?
- Mom... Mom...
Mom, I'm sorry.
But the truth is...
The truth is...
You were supposed to be dead.
What do you mean?
Mom, you didn't recover from your illness.
You were supposed to be dead, Mom.
But of all the changes I made...
you're the only one who turned out right.
And you, Joyce.
Joyce?
All your dreams, everything you saw,
all your visions, they are all real.
You died at the second revision of our lives.
You died while we were filming.
You learned about Congressman Ramon's secret.
Uncle Edmond used to work
for Congressman Ramon.
Uncle Edmond gave you that information.
But because I used the typewriter,
everything changed.
Everything changed. I saved your life.
You didn't die.
But there was a price to pay.
I saved your life,
but they took it out on Uncle Edmond.
He went blind.
And in my desire
to bring you back to life, Joyce...
Sep died instead.
Sep died helplessly.
Everything happened because...
Because of that cursed typewriter
that our family owned?
It's so hard to believe
everything you just said, son.
But I know...
I know that you won't make up
such a story, right, son?
Yes, Mom.
Joyce?
Did I really die?
I asked you before, Liam.
I asked you if what I saw was true.
Did I really die?
Someone killed Sep.
They took it out on my father,
that's why he got blind?
What if I want to file a case?
What should I tell the court?
What testimony should I give them?
That it was because of the typewriter?
What do I tell them?
That you did nothing wrong
aside from writing?
I'm sorry, Liam.
I want to believe you,
but my heart isn't ready yet.
Excuse me. Aunt Tess, I'll get going.
Joyce.
You know my biggest fear, Hans...
is to be alone.
Why would you be alone?
Many people love and admire you.
You really believe that?
Yes.
Can't you admit that your world
only revolves around Joyce?
And then, poof!
Just like that.
In the blink of an eye, you lost her.
Joyce and Liam will eventually
come back to their senses.
Are we just going to wait until then?
We can do something.
So we can mark what's ours.
Via...
What do you mean?
What I'm saying is
we have to fight for what's ours.
We give our best for our relationship.
They've just met.
I want to love Joyce the right way.
Hans, oh my God. Wake up.
What are you talking about?
I gave everything to Liam.
I did everything for him.
Yet I was left alone.
Don't be stupid.
Hans, you have to fight.
Come on.
My half-brother, Vergil Herrera...
He's the one who took over
my position in Casa Fuerte.
All the money from all the illegal businesses
of Congressman Ramon dela Peña
is getting laundered in Casa Fuerte.